steinberg.net 2018-03-28

# Privacy Policy | Steinberg

## Personal information

Personal information encompasses individual details about personal or business relations of a specific or specifiable natural person (data subject), e.g. your own personal information such as name, address, telephone number and date of birth.

## Anonymous data collection

In principle, you can visit our web pages without informing us who you are. When our pages are viewed we automatically register your IP address or the domain name of the user as well as which pages are viewed. We use this information to statistically evaluate the usage of our site by our visitors and to continuously improve our web pages using the gained insights. For this reason we are using the Google Analytics software. In this process you will remain anonymous as individual user.

## eTracker

This website uses etracker technology ([www.etracker.com](http://www.etracker.com/)) to collect visitor behavior data. This data is collected anonymously to be used for marketing and optimization purposes. All visitor data is saved using an anonymous user ID and can be aggregated to a usage profile. Cookies may be used to collect and save this data, but the data remains strictly anonymous. The data will not be used to identify a visitor personally and are not aggregated with any personal data. The collection and storage of data may be [refused](https://www.etracker.de/privacy?et=bssZBV) at any time with respect to subsequent services. [](https://www.etracker.de/privacy?et=bssZBV)

_We use the following technology of Google Inc. (1600 Amphitheater Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA; ‘Google’):_

## Google Analytics and Conversion Tracking

This website uses Google Analytics, a web analysis service provided by Google Inc. (“Google”). Google Analytics uses “cookies”; these are text files which are stored on your computer to analyse the way you use the website. 

The Hamburg Commissioner for Data Protection and Freedom of Information reached an agreement with Google based on the decision of the Düsseldorf Group on data protection. According to this, a compliant use of analytical methods of reach measurement of Internet advertisements is now possible under certain conditions. Therefore, it is possible to use Google Analytics in a manner which is compliant with the law and does not raise any concerns. We do, of course, comply with these requirements. In particular, we point out that Google Analytics has been extended by the code “{ 'anonymize_ip': true }” on this website to guarantee the anonymized collection of IP addresses (so-called IP-masking). Google will first truncate your IP address in Member States of the European Union or in other state parties to the Agreement on the European Economic Area. Only in exceptional cases is the full IP address sent to and truncated on a Google server in the USA. Google uses this information on behalf of the website operator to evaluate the way you use the website, to collate reports on website activities and to provide the website operator other services related to website and Internet use. The IP address sent by your browser as part of Google Analytics is not combined with other data held by Google. 

Further information concerning the terms and conditions of use and data privacy can be found at <http://www.google.com/analytics/terms/gb.html> or at <https://www.google.de/intl/en_uk/policies/>. 

The information about the way you use this website created by the cookie is sent to and stored on a Google server in the USA. You can change your browser settings to prevent cookies from being stored; however, we draw your attention to the fact that, in these circumstances, you may find that you are unable to make full use of functions on the website. You can also prevent the data (including your IP address) relating to your use of the website which is captured by the cookie being sent to or processed by Google by downloading and installing the browser plug-in from the following link <https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en>. You can refuse the use of Google Analytics by clicking on the following link. An opt-out cookie will be set on the computer, which prevents the future collection of your data when visiting this website: [Deactivate Google Analytics](http://javascript:gaOptout\(\) "Öffnet externen Link in neuem Fenster")

We also use Google Conversion Tracking for Google Analytics. This allows us to capture the behavior of our website visitors. For example, we will see how many PDFs were downloaded on our website or how often the contact form was filled out. We also report how many clicks on ads from external sources (AdWords, LinkedIn, Xing, Bing) have led to our website.

 _We use the following technology of Google Inc. (1600 Amphitheater Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA; ‘Google’):_

## Google Tag Manager

For reasons of transparency, please note that we use Google Tag Manager. Google Tag Manager does not collect personally identifiable information. The tag manager makes it easier for us to integrate and manage our tags. Tags are small code elements that are used to measure traffic and visitor behavior, capture the impact of online advertising and social channels, set up remarketing and target audience targeting, and test and optimize web pages. We use the Tag Manager for the Google Service “Google Analytics”. If you have disabled, Google Tag Manager will consider this deactivation. For more information about Google Tag Manager, see: <https://www.google.com/intl/en-uk/tagmanager/use-policy.html>

## Collection, processing and disclosure of personal data

In some areas of our website we request personal data from you to help us identify you as a person. Normally this will involve so-called inventory data, i.e. such personal information of a user required for the justification, design of content, or change of a contractual relationship in regards to our Tele/Media service. Such inventory data are collected for example when you create a user account and/or register Steinberg products, but also if you wish to participate in our chat room or our forums. 

We process these inventory data in such a fashion that the highest possible privacy of your personal data is safeguarded. Using authentication and authorization procedures, we ensure as much as possible that unauthorized individuals have no access to your personal data or use services that are exclusive to you. In addition, we collect your personal information always then and to the extent required for the contractual purpose e.g. when you participate in our competitions and we need your address data for a possible notification of winning. 

Your personal data will be transferred to our associated companies and service providers, e.g. IT providers and others who are subject to our instructions and who help us provide the services to you. Through appropriate legal, technical and organizational measures as well as through a regular monitoring thereof we ensure compliance with the applicable data protection laws and an adequate level of data protection where personal data is transferred to service providers located outside the European Union and the European Economic Area. Involved service providers will only get access to those specific personal data that is required to fulfill their services. They do not have the right to use your information for their own purposes, especially promotional activities. 

Only with your explicit consent do we pass on personal information to third parties (e.g. our distributors) especially when these third parties have their domicile outside of the states covered by European Union law. Also we will only contact you in an unsolicited way by means of the personal information stored on our servers if you have given your explicit consent to do so. 

## Consent and use of data only for the purpose stated

In as far as you are asked to enter personal information (e.g. email addresses, names, addresses) on one of our web pages, the submission of these data (Submit) is strictly on a voluntary basis. In these cases, we ask your explicit consent whilst stating the purpose of use. We do not collect, process, or use this data for other purposes without your express consent. 

At any time you can revoke your consent which will become effective in the future. 

## Cookies

Cookies help us tailor our web pages to your needs. Cookies are text files containing information which your web browser stores on your computer when you open a web page. 

We use this cookie technology to tailor our web pages to your language and preferred areas of interest. If you do not want this, you can simply disable cookies in your browser. Most browsers accept cookies by default but provide you with options to disallow cookies or to show a warning before storing them. 

## Access right and public procedure directory

Upon request, we communicate to you in written form — in compliance with applicable law — if we have personal information stored from you and if so, which data. In addition you have the right to rectification, blocking, and deletion of this personal information. 

In our public procedure directory we have summarized the details as per section 4e of the Bundesdatenschutzgesetzes (Federal Data Protection Act - BDSG). Our commissioner for data protection will be happy to open this procedure directory should you express the desire to do so to him. 

## Security

We apply technical and organizational security measures to protect personal information from accidental or intended manipulation, loss, destruction, or access by unauthorized persons. We adjust our security measures to align with technological developments and improve them on a continuous basis to ensure the highest possible safety standard. 

You can contribute towards the security of the personal information stored on our servers by for example safekeeping the passwords to access our services and to not pass them on to third parties without checking, even when these claim to be Steinberg employees. Steinberg employees will never ask you for a password. 

## Company data protection commissioner

Should you have questions regarding the processing of your personal information, you can directly contact our commissioner for data protection who can also be of service with informational inquiries, requests, or complaints: 

The data protection commissioner will only answer questions regarding our privacy policy **and will not respond to any product support related issues.**

Note:   
By means of his public key you can send the data protection commissioner your concerns encrypted per email. If you include the public key in your encryption program (e.g. openPGP) and encrypt your data with the key, the encrypted data can only be opened by our commissioner for data protection. 

Last updated: July 2008
